so to start i've just attached this
clasp um onto the wall so it's easier to
demonstrate
and i'm going to take my cord and i fold
it in half so that's the center point
and i'm going to go behind over that
part
down and then pull the cords through
and we're going to do that same knot so
a reverse larks head knot
with all four cords
now the first rows are going to come out
close to the top not too diagonal and
how we're going to do it
is we're going to take divide it into 2
so four on this side
four on this side and i'm going to take
this one so the fifth chord in
and there are three behind it and you're
gonna use that as my guide
i'm gonna put it right about there and
we're gonna do
double hitch knots over that one so i'll
take the very next cord
put it over like that and i'm gonna pull
it through that loop
and for each you do that twice to close
off the knot
there's the first one and now the second
[Music]
one
i like to just push it up with my thumb
just to get it into place
now that we have our first row done
we're going to do the exact same thing
in the opposite direction so we have
these four chords
i'm going to take the fourth one and i'm
going to point it this way
and that will be our guide rope and
we're going to do the same as this side
so you take the first one put it over
through
and tighten it we're going to do that
again so over
through
and tighten it and go all the way to the
end
now you want to make sure that these are
pretty close to even they don't have to
be perfect but just so that one side's
not up like this and the others down
like that
now to do the next row so see we have
four again on each side we're just going
to take
the very first one that comes out here
and we're going to pull it down that way
and we're going to pull this
first cord there we're going to pull it
all the way up
we're going to leave a little space with
the second and then a tiny bit more with
the third
so see i'm just leaving that little
amount of space there just so i'm not
pulling it up as tight as that one
okay so you can see both sides are
pretty much even we left the space there
a little bit of space there and now
we're going to repeat the same steps and
we're always starting with the very
first chord
so now that we've done one two and three
the sides are looking pretty
even although i want to tighten that one
up a little bit
um now we're going to do the last one
and this one can be a little bit closer
than the previous ones
now that we have one two three four rows
on each side we are going to do a
tiny gathering knot to close it off and
i have about
i'd say it's about eight to ten inches
and what we're gonna do
is because all of these are there i'm
just gonna push them back nicely
until we get a nice closed center like
that
and i'm going to turn it around and try
to keep everything in place
and then with that scrap piece i have
i'm just going to make a tiny little
loop
down there i hope you can see that and
now i'm just gonna wrap it around
and i'm gonna check to make sure it's
around the bottom of the
two last knots i'm going to go once
and twice now if you want to do more and
you want the gathering knot to be
bigger or longer you can do
more times round i'm just going to push
that piece
through that little loop that we made
it's giving me some trouble
and i'm going to hold it nice and tight
while i pull that little
upper piece out
now i will cut off that bottom one
one last tug just to hide it a little
okay now you can see that one's poking
up a bit so i'm just going to
find it down here give it a little tug
to make it even
perfect and now i will decide the length
of fringe that i want and for myself i'm
going to go down about
two inches
now you're more than welcome to leave
the fringe like that but for myself i
use
a metal pet comb and i just give it a
good brushing out
you